TYLER REHM

1142 Mazarion Place New Port Richey, FL, 34655 m: 727.457.2232 tylerrehm@q.harvard.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven change agent with career-long record of web design, software engineering, and digital customization success for leading organizations

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established digital analysis and web application management paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused thought leader with expertise spanning web development, SaaS design, business systems analysis, technology solutions, software design and implementation, cross-functional team leadership, automatic systems development, electronic document management, and client relationship management. Exceptional administrator with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TRADER PLANET, WESLEY CHAPEL, FL, AUGUST 2015 TO PRESENT

SENIOR WEB APPLICATION ENGINEER

- Enhance and maintain financial trading and informational products utilized by over 80,000 users, integrating multiple web APIs, external content and collaboration tools, focusing on seamless advertising campaigns and non-intrusive revenue generation techniques.
- Structure and build web interfaces, conceptual designs, and automation services, ensuring consistency, accuracy, and compliance with industry and company standards.
- Refactor legacy sites and functionalities, fusing new technologies and frameworks that improve back-end performance, usability, and aesthetics, including frameworks, library extensions, and language overhauls, continually enhancing neural networks and algorithms.
- Administer underlying server technologies and monitoring services, ensuring 99.97% SLA and associated virtual machine configuration, resource management, network availability, failover systems and Linux-based tools.
- Create documentation, maintain forms, stylesheets, related data schemas and applicable executive management reporting requirements.

HEALTH AXIS GROUP, TAMPA, FL, DECEMBER 2013 TO FEBRUARY 2016

SENIOR LEAD DEVELOPER

- Develop, implement, and maintain several interoperating applications that make up a cloud-based SaaS healthcare patient reminder service and EHR interface.
- Automate and re-engineer, test, and deploy software platform that delivers over 4000 appointment reminders per day including voice, sms, and email messages, re-writing original PHP source code in C# and saving the company approximately \$32,000 per year.
- Conceive, update, and preserve library of user and technical documentation for reminder service application, internal process standardization, interface protocols, and data statistics.
- Amend and monitor provider directory of over 30,000 providers and locations integrating Google Maps API and file processing infrastructure.

LOTTEREASE, TAMPA, FL, APRIL 2014 TO JUNE 2015

DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

- Built, optimized, and enhanced cloud-based SaaS platform based on MVC framework reducing manual processing of lotteries from 40 hours to nearly 2 hours.
- Designed and oversaw client facing web interface used by several different user types, including admin, client, customers, and demo users.

TYLER REHM Page 2

KASS-SHULER-SOLOMAN-SPECTOR-SINGER, P.A., TAMPA, FL, APRIL 2013 TO DECEMBER 2014

BUSINESS SYSTEMS ANALYST CONTRACTOR

• Renewed, edited, and created automated legal file merge documents as per client requests, internal updates, and industry standards changes utilizing database data merges and macro object creation.

- Architected and refurbished automated Crystal Reports designed to track and aggregate account, proceeding, trial and deadline data for attorneys, process analyst, quality assurance and managers.
- Fulfilled development and support-related IT tickets for database alterations and updates, system bugs and enhancements, and general maintenance tasks.

FOWLER-WHITE-BOGGS, P.A., TAMPA, FL, OCTOBER 2011 TO APRIL 2013

ELECTRONIC DOCUMENT MANAGEMENT ANALYST

- Produced professional legal documentation templates, indexing, and reports while working directly with attorneys, paralegals, legal assistants and management.
- Transmitted and maintained traditional hard-copy documents into electronic versions maintained internally via company database and intranet for several regional offices.
- Coordinated indexed file system workflow and document transfer, storage, and destruction.

PUBLIX SUPERMARKETS, TRINITY, FL, JANUARY 2010 TO JULY 2012

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

- Guaranteed overall customer satisfaction including conflict resolution, greeting and assisting
 customers, weighing, scanning, and packaging groceries, handling cash and operating point of sale
 terminal.
- Restored store front, organized inventory displays, delivered groceries and special requests to customer vehicles, and retrieved shopping carts and trash from parking lot and public areas.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

MASTER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (M.I.T.) IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, IN PROGRESS

Harvard University, Cambridge, MA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN BUSINESS ECONOMICS, 2014 University of South Florida, Tampa, FL

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS, 2014 University of South Florida, Tampa, FL

EDUCATION ABROAD EXPERIENCES

- Software Engineering at InfoSys, Bangalore, India, Summer 2013
- National & Competitive Intelligence, Tel Aviv, Israel, Summer 2013
- Business Enterprises at Florence University of the Arts, Florence, Italy, Summer 2012

TECHNICAL ACUMEN

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCIES: PHP, C#, Perl, Python, R, Go, Ruby

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery; Ajax, ASP.Net

DATABASE: MS-SQL, MySQL

TYLER REHM Page 3

OTHER: Google Maps API, JSON, VBScript, XML, SOAP, Batch Scripts (.bat), RESTful API Twilio API, SaleForce API, Authorize.net API, Stripe API, Google Analytics API, CloudFlare, AWS, Docker

<u>SOFTWARE APPLICATIONS:</u> Visual Studio, Eclipse, FileZilla, WinSCP, MS Office, MS Visio, PuTTy, TortoiseSVN, Cmder, SoapUI, VoiceGuide, FrontLineSMS, KeePass, TightVNC, HeidiSQL, WireShark, PhpStorm, Sublime Text

<u>SOFTWARE PLATFORMS:</u> Microsoft Windows 8, Linux (Ubuntu/ RedHat/CentOS), GitHub SVN, LogMeIn Rescue, GoToMeeting, Selenium, PHP Codeception TDD; LAMP stack, Drupal 7, RackSpace, New Relic, WordPress, Artisan, Gulp, Elixir

SOFTWARE FRAMEWORKS: PHP Laravel 5 MVC, Twitter Bootstrap, CakePHP, SlimPHP

AWARDS AND HONORS

- College of Business 25 Under 25
- Florida Academic Scholar
- Vincent & Heidi Bekiempis Endowment
- Honors College Travel Award
- Undergraduate Research Scholarship
- Bulls Business Community Scholar
- Honors College Undergraduate Scholar
- USF Directors Award
- ISDS Practice Center Study Abroad Scholarship
- Honors College Studen

- Wendy's High School Heisman
- College of Business Undergraduate Scholar
- Inaugural Business Honors Member
- · College of Business Dean's List
- Corporate Mentor Program
- Omicron Delta Epsilon Economic Honors Society Member
- National & Competitive Intelligence Analysis International Seminar Attendee
- J.W. Mitchell High School Anne Frank Humanitarian Award Finalist

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS

- President of the USF Ice Hockey Team
- Sports Club Council Executive Board Chairman
- Co-Founder and Vice President of Event Management for Noble Guides
- Treasurer of the USF Roller Hockey Team

VOLUNTEERISM

- Sports & Steak Day Volunteer
- Terrace Community Middle School Volunteer
- Team Raider's Youth Development Volunteer
- Maddi Goss Charity Ice Hockey Tournament Coordinator, Bulls Business Community Mentor
- USF Resident Hall Move-In Volunteer

References Available Upon Request